MANSVINI AGGARWAL

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

A problem-solver with 2 years of experience in leading businesses looking to leverage communication skills as a software/full stack engineer. Coding since the age of 11 with experience in building complex modules and deploying projects using React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, APIs, Heroku, and GitHub using best practices like CI, tests, code reviews, and good design practices. B.tech in Electronics & Communications Engineering.

FIND ME ONLINE

3

Portfolio

https://mansvini.netlify.app/



https://github.com/Mansvini

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Open Source Contributor

Zero To Mastery

A global open source playground for the coding community

- Collaborating with community managers and developers from around the world on GitHub and Discord.
- Contributed to ZTM Job Board project using SCSS, HTML & JavaScript.
- Participated in the Animation Nation Hacktober project where the challenge was to use only CSS.

Co-founder

Health Blis 12/2019 - 09/2021

A B2B startup in the pharma industry

- Handling end-to-end design and development of websites while regularly updating and maintaining them.
- Testing, deploying and observing content management system to production servers which led to a better User Experience.
- Communicating and collaborating with 200+ stakeholders to build a supply chain which led to a ROI of 16% within 3 months.

Core Team Member

Honest Farmer 06/2018 - 03/2019

A zero-waste supply chain to supply produce from farms to customers within 24 hours of harvesting

- Solved the problem of drain water irrigation and food traceability by building the world's fastest 100% traceable food supply chain.
- Working with the core team while managing a group of 6-8 people.
- Brainstorming solutions creatively while handling operations.
- Acquired 200+ customers from a single locality by communication and marketing which converted to 30% regular customers.

Information Technology (IT) Intern

Oil & Natural Gas Corporation (ONGC) 06/2017 - 07/2017

- · Learnt the functioning of ONGC, SAP ERP, and SAP ABAP.
- Built an Online Quiz Software on SAP using the ABAP language.

Embedded Systems Intern

IBM 06/2016 - 07/2016

- Learnt about the practical applications of Embedded Systems.
- Built the project <u>Data monitoring using GSM Module</u> with AVR AT Mega 16, sensors, GSM module and C++.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

Smart Brain using ML API

A web app built using React.js as front-end framework, and RESTful API server with Express.js for backend. Stores user information along with hashed passwords securely in a Postgresql database. Deployed on Heroku.

IOT based portable health monitor

A health monitor which uses sensors, Arduino and C++ to track the vital signs of patients. This app is connected to IOT and can be monitored from anywhere in the world. This is a lifesaver which signals the connected devices in case of an emergency.

EDUCATION

The Complete Web Developer

Zero to Mastery Academy

10/2021 - 02/2022

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech)-Electronics & Communications Engineering (ECE)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIPU)

09/2014 - 08/2018

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer

The Art of Living

06/2018 - Ongoing

- Taught about the importance of mental health to 250+ youth.
- Worked with a team and mentors to conduct events for various social causes.
- Continuously organised 10+ workshops for 50+ participants.